lc-tech.com 2019-03-09

# Privacy Policy of LC Technology - File Recovery Software and Services

### LC Technology Privacy Policy

 ** **Data Recovery Services:**  
Our data recovery lab is a secure environment with all customer data kept private and controlled laboratory access to ensure only appropriate specialists handle sensitive information. We are regularly contracted to recover classified data for the government, law enforcement agencies and private organizations. LC Technology is accustomed to the level of privacy and protection that classified materials require. All recovered documents are permanently wiped after 30 days.**

 ** **Purpose:** LC Technology International’s privacy policy statement was written as a guide to the information we collect from users and how we use that information. We feel this will allow them to make an educated and comfortable decision to supply information to us. If you have any questions comments or concerns please let us know at Service@LC-Tech.com.**

Statistic Tracking  
Cookies  
Demographic and personal information we request  
How we use collected information  
Who we share information with

 **Statistics Tracking:** LC Technology operates 4 main sites, [www.LC-Tech.com](https://www.lc-tech.com/), [www.LC-Tech.co.uk](http://www.lc-tech.co.uk/), [www.FILERECOVERY.com](http://filerecovery.com/) and [www.PHOTORECOVERY.us](http://photorecovery.us/) All sites track statistics. The sites run on Windows® 2003 Server with Extended Logging. IIS captures IP Address and referring URL as well as keywords used in major search engines such as MSN, Yahoo, and Google. The statistics also track pages viewed, how long they are viewed, session time and other statistics. This information is used internally only to manage the user experience better. We do not publish or in anyway make our statistics public. We may, on occasion list how many visitors or hits our site has handled in a given time period, but no specific information on individual IP addresses is released. Our statistics are compiled and tracked with LiveStats XSP, it will do a reverse DNS lookup and display a machine name and origin. This is used for regional Demographics only and is not stored, nor shared.

 **Cookies:** We only use cookies in the e-commerce area of our site. Cookies are used to keep track of the shopping cart contents and the buying session. The cookies are also used to help fill in forms automatically. The cookies do not send any information and expire in a few days.

 **Demographic Information and Personal Information We Request:** We request personal information in several areas of our website; when Demos are downloaded, information is requested, products are purchased, technical support is requested or a subscription to our newsletter is requested. Along with personal information we also request basic Demographic information and/or a description of the problem you are having. All mailing lists are opt-in and the user can unsubscribe at anytime by sending an e-Mail to Unsubscribe@LC-Tech.com to be immediately removed.

 **How We Use Collected Information:** Any information collected on our website, whether submitted by the user or collected by the statistics server is used strictly in-house for Demographic analysis, product improvement and enhanced user experience. We do have a monthly newsletter which is opt-in by e-Mail. We do not spam or bulk e-Mail offers or advertising nor do we sell or distribute our list to any third party persons or companies. We keep all information strictly confidential.

 **Who We Share Information With:** The only third parties who have any access to information about our customers is First Data Corporation through their E4 Global Gateway credit card processing gateway, with PayPal and SanDisk® Corporation. Information is sent to E4 Global Gateway only when a customer makes a purchase and we use a secure transaction gateway. First Data Corporation (E4 Global Gateway’s Parent Company) is one of the largest credit card processors in the world and operates in 34 countries around the world. You can view their information [here](https://www.firstdata.com/en_us/about-first-data/media/first-data-facts.html). First Data has verbally verified they do not share information and that it is against the card issuers policy, which does not allow them to share any billing information. LC Technology cannot back any policy by E4 Global Gateway or First Data. Information is sent to SanDisk® Corporation only when a customer has purchased SanDisk® RescuePRO® directly from www.LC-Tech.com. SanDisk® Corporation is one of the largest producers and suppliers of flash storage card products for a wide variety of electronic products and digital devices. LC Technology International cannot back any policy by SanDisk® Corporation.

 **What Rights You Have Over Your Data:**

If you are a registered user or have left comments on our site you can request to see or download the data we have about you. As LC-Tech.com does not take comments, or have registered users, we would not have information of this sort for a visitor to download. The only information we would have would be the information supplied from filling out a software evaluation request form, a support request form, or a contact form.

Typically for visitors that have filled out a form, the data will be their email address, any IP addresses assigned to them at the time of filling out a form and the user agent strings of the browsers they used. The rest of the data is public as published by the visitors.

For paying customers, this will also include profile information and download, payment, and support ticket histories.

You can also request “to be forgotten” and we will erase any personally identifiable data we have about you. Of course, this excludes data we need for administrative or security purposes or if we are required by law to retain some of the data. For the present time period, this applies to our visitors from the European Union, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We will amend this further in the near future.

An individual who seeks access, or who seeks to correct, amend, or delete inaccurate data, should direct his/her query to [support@lc-tech.com](mailto:support@lc-tech.com). We will respond within a reasonable timeframe, not to exceed one week. For the present time period, this applies to our visitors from the European Union, in accordance with the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). We will amend this further in the near future.

 **What Data Breach Procedures We Have In Place:**

Should any event occur where customer data has been lost, stolen, or potentially compromised, our policy is to alert our customers via email no later than 48 hours of our team becomes aware of the event. We will also report such incident to any required data protection authority. We will work closely with any customers affected to determine next steps such as any end-user notifications, and how to avoid any similar event in the future.

 **Contact Information:**

Customer Service – Service@LC-Tech.com  
Cancel subscription – Unsubscribe@LC-Tech.com  
Phone Us – Toll Free (866) 603-2195  
FirstData Contact – [Click Here](https://www.firstdata.com/en_us/contact.html)
